ADAPTED FROM THE BLOSSOMING LOVE
BY SUI YU ER AN ON ICEREAD.COM
If I feared death,
I wouldn't be standing here now.
Between killing Hao Tian
and being controlled by him,
I choose the former.
Let's begin.
THOUSANDS OF YEARS AGO, DONGZE PALACE
Zhao Ming.
TWILIGHT SPIRIT PAVILION
So,
Zhao Ming will ascend alone
to slay deities,
bearing the suffering for 10,000 years.
If only…
If I had helped him
fight the deities sooner,
could this tragedy have been avoided?
The cause and effect of history
has already unfolded.
It cannot be undone.
History's course must not be altered.
Otherwise,
the world that follows will collapse.
Upon Hao Tian's descent,
everything will be unknown.
If all goes well,
we can save ourselves
after killing Hao Tian.
Or perhaps, we will save the world,
only to perish with Hao Tian.
Protecting all beings
has always been my duty.
This life of mine no longer belongs to me.
This game is about the entire world.
Failure is not an option.
Remember, before Zhao Ming
ascends to slay deities,
make sure Hao Tian possesses Zhao Ming.
Only in this way
can we create Hao Tian's form in your time
and bring about
the mutual killing of two Hao Tians.
At that time, you must help him
complete the final step.
Hao Tian does not suspect me yet.
It won't be hard to act.
But I'm worried about you.
Hao Tian has already
noticed your betrayal,
so you must be more careful.
Now that you know everything
in the following 10,000 years,
do you regret it?
What about you?
After enduring 10,000 years of pain,
why are you still willing
to risk it all for the world?
After my fate changed,
dark thoughts began to arise.
The blood on my hands
must eventually be paid back.
I must restore
a clean Zhao Ming
to Pearl and to this world.
What more can I do?
Since you already know
this farewell is inevitable,
you should cherish
the last moments together.
Don't leave behind
unfixable regrets like I did.
I never expected
that the cause of Zhao Ming, I, and Fate
would make you bear this suffering
10,000 years later.
I owe you an apology.
No.
Pearl,
I should thank you.
You exhausted your power,
leaving Zhao Ming's soul,
so I could meet Xie Xuechen.
Xie Xuechen…
What kind of person is he?
He…
He's a good person.
Is he as good as Zhao Ming?
In your heart,
Zhao Ming is naturally the best.
But in my heart,
Xie Xuechen is unique,
the best person in the world.
He already died to save me,
and I will do everything I can
to protect his world.
I never thought
that 10,000 years later, I would have
to resort to such desperate measures
to combat the world-ending disaster.
Though I've glimpsed
the cause and effect of all things,
I never predicted the true ending.
I once believed in fate,
but now I believe even more
that the true ending is in our own hands.
The decision made
10,000 years ago was mine,
but the pain, the suffering,
and the humiliation
for 10,000 years was borne by you.
During these 10,000 years,
you've endured so much.
From the beginning of chaos,
we were controlled by Hao Tian.
This battle against Hao Tian
truly has an uncertain outcome.
All of this
shouldn't have been yours to bear.
I have nothing left to lose.
Moreover,
this is the only way to protect the world.
No matter what,
I will give my all.
To protect the world we swore to defend,
I will follow the established course,
every step as planned.
After 10,000 years of rebirth,
enduring the emotional curse
and meeting the old friend again,
have you ever realized
what love really is?
Love…
Love cannot be comprehended.
Bound for 10,000 years,
yet love remains beyond understanding.
As I thought,
though we control fate,
we are destined to live without love.
Love has no fixed definition.
It arises from the heart.
Sometimes,
love is obsession,
is to take hold,
and sometimes,
love is release,
is letting go.
Letting go?
After 10,000 years,
having experienced the mortal world,
now I seem to believe
that humans
can defy fate.
Hao Tian,
in this world, there is only
endless ignorance and slaughter.
I humbly invite Your Grace to possess
my body to destroy this broken world
and create a new era.
The world is decaying,
and human nature is cold and indifferent.
In this life, guarding the world
is all a misdirected sacrifice.
EVERBRIGHT PALACE
I, Zhao Ming,
am willing to assist Your Grace.
I humbly invite Your Grace to possess me.
The Timekeeper stabilizes time and space,
and the Fatekeeper
stabilizes cause and effect.
Now is the time for us to work together.
Are you ready?
No need to prepare.
Since the beginning of chaos,
we have already been cooperating
for tens of thousands of years.
Beginning is the end.
The starting point
is also the ending point.
The beginning and end are intertwined,
repeating endlessly.
The chance of life
lies in the moment of our reunion.
I never expected
that they would figure out this method.
But trying to defy me with human strength
is truly overestimating themselves.
These arrogant ones must pay the price.
Let them be forever condemned.
Revered Saint Emperor,
do you truly understand yourself?
Though you hide your reluctance
anger, and rebellion
deep in your heart,
do you think they do not exist?
No,
the Demon Lord is the best proof.
He… is your dark side.
Zhao Ming is the Saint Emperor,
loved by the masses,
and you are the fallen demon
of the Dark Abyss, despised by the world.
You are Zhao Ming's shame,
the burden he most wishes to abandon.
What the world needs is the Saint Emperor,
not the Demon Lord.
Everyone calls you noble and selfless,
but when the ministers betray,
and the people turn away,
you truly feel no hatred?
When you separated from Pearl
to save the world,
you truly feel no regret?
You feel anger, obsession, and regret.
It's simply impossible
for you to remain pure forever.
Pearl awaited Zhao Ming,
Mu Xuanling awaited Xie Xuechen,
and you, the fallen Demon Lord,
with no loved ones, no friends,
only seen as Zhao Ming's dark thoughts.
Your existence is utterly meaningless!
Zhao Ming's heart is clear,
and the Demon Lord's heart
has been released.
How could they still
be deceived by Hao Tian?
There is no one in this world
without inner demons.
As long as there is desire in the heart,
something to cling to,
something to yearn for,
Hao Tian will find the flaw.
If this continues,
the incense will burn out soon.
This is exactly Hao Tian's plan.
Once this incense burns out,
the two Hao Tians
will return to their respective timelines
and once again rule the world.
We cannot let Hao Tian succeed.
We must find a way to awaken them quickly.
The rule-free zone
lies beyond our time and space.
We can't intervene.
The incense time is almost up.
If we can't kill Hao Tian now,
the world will be destroyed.
Nan Xuyue, I have a plan.
My true form is the Timekeeper artifact,
not bound by time and space.
I will give you all the power of Chaos.
You must stabilize time and space here,
send my true form into the rule-free zone,
and help them fight Hao Tians.
No!
Your true form will perish
with the collapse of the rule-free zone.
-It's better to follow my plan.
-What is it?
The artifact's destruction
will cause a brief change
in time and space.
The passage
to the rule-free zone will reopen.
At that time,
you can send your and Pearl's mind
into the rule-free zone,
while your true form
stays here,
stabilizing time and space.
The artifact's destruction…
What will you do?
You're burning your true form…
You will die!
Let's think of another way!
I once thought
that as ancient artifacts,
our duty was to uphold Hao Tian's order.
The survival of this world
has nothing to do with us.
Until I followed you to the mortal realm,
experienced the human life,
and felt a hint of warmth
and desire,
I began to hesitate.
Perhaps the rules of this world
can be set by Hao Tian,
but the most precious love
in the human heart
is something even heaven cannot control.
I also know very well
I no longer wish to be Hao Tian's pawn,
nor do I wish to see you
and this world
be destroyed together.
-Nan Xuyue!
-Mu Xuanling,
the you I know
has never been hesitant.
You've always known
what the best choice was.
And now,
you should be the same.
Meeting you for the first time
felt like greeting an old friend.
Under a distant, renewed moon,
you are my…
dawn-to-dusk longing.
You promised…
to give me a little bit of liking.
I can give you what you want,
including…
that little bit of liking.
Mu Xuanling,
go and fulfill your desires.
Nan Xuyue…
Through these 10,000 years…
you've never lived a day for yourself.
Now, you're finally free.
Nan Xuyue,
you sacrificed yourself
to fulfill all this.
I will not let you down.
EVERBRIGHT PALACE
Wake up. Don't be deceived by Hao Tian.
Zhao Ming, don't be deceived by him.
Everything in this world has its opposite,
just like love and hate,
right and wrong, black and white.
When sunlight shines on someone,
shadows are cast.
You already know the truth.
Whether in the past
or in the present,
we have never betrayed you.
But the fault lies neither
with the sunlight nor with the shadow,
nor with you, who stand in its light!
Listen, how deceitful she is.
She loves the Beacon of Righteousness,
Xie Xuechen.
She's here now to help you,
but only to bring Xie Xuechen back.
What does that have to do with you?
See how she pretends?
She is an ancient artifact.
She has been on the Celestial Altar
for tens of thousands of years,
observing countless lives and deaths,
good and evil.
In fact, being emotionless
is her true nature.
The rules are her fate.
You two are destined to be
on different paths.
You and I
are the ones
who understand each other the most.
We have no family,
and we've both lost our loved ones.
Though I have Pearl's memories,
I am not her.
You also have Xie Xuechen's memories,
but you are not him.
I understand you,
just as I understand myself.
Understanding?
You've always been wrong!
As the ruler,
you've disregarded life for 10,000 years,
slaughtering the world.
What is the difference
between your actions and those of demons?
If Hao Tian is unkind
and deities are heartless,
then this world doesn't need you!
It doesn't need us?
Think carefully.
The human race
you once protected betrayed you.
Even the Chaos Pearl,
nurtured with blood essence by you,
eventually betrayed you, didn't it?
It was she
who pushed you into the deepest abyss.
What's left to trust in her?
Ten thousand years ago,
you were suppressed by Fate,
falling from a revered
Saint Emperor into a Fallen Deity.
Who ever gave you the chance to choose?
Zhao Ming,
whether to do good or evil,
the choice has always been yours.
You must know all this better than I do.
We've come here today,
no matter the cost, not for ourselves.
Just now, to bring me and Pearl in,
Nan Xuyue has already fallen.
Wake up,
otherwise all the sacrifices and efforts
will have been in vain.
I fell to the mortal realm
after repairing the heavens.
You warmed the heart of that pearl.
You taught that pearl… what love is.
Now, I've regained my memory and power.
This time,
let me stand by your side
and break all these unjust rules
of Hao Tian.
You once asked me for the power of Chaos.
I refused to give it to you
because I hope
that you can see who you really are first.
Now,
I, Mu Xuanling,
am willing to use the power of Chaos
to help you break through the universe
and recreate the heavens and earth.
After the strongest clash,
both Hao Tians have been completely gone.
Then,
what will our ending be?
No matter the outcome,
if one of you survives,
the Demon Lord or Zhao Ming,
you must return to the time
of 10,000 years ago
and follow the original course
to walk history again
to preserve the future.
This method has never been tried before.
Everything must be decided
according to the situation.
Does Xie Xuechen's soul…
truly not exist anymore?
I'll say this once more.
Xie Xuechen's soul
has been completely integrated by me.
Have you ever considered
that with Xie Xuechen's soul fragment,
your power may surpass Zhao Ming's?
If your fight ends in life or death,
the one who survives…
may very well be you.
Hao Tian is dead.
The world-ending crisis has been solved.
The world has been saved.
I die without regret.
But the established
cause and effect already exist
and cannot be changed.
Future generations of people,
events, and objects
are all derived and inherited
from 10,000 years ago.
The major historical course back then
must not shift.
Otherwise,
the entire future will collapse.
The incense has burned out.
With the restoration of time and space,
you'll return to 10,000 years ago.
Whether to walk the old path again,
this time, the final choice is yours.
Zhao Ming.
Pearl awaits Zhao Ming,
Mu Xuanling waits for Xie Xuechen,
and you, the fallen Demon Lord,
with no loved ones, no friends,
only seen as Zhao Ming's dark thoughts.
Your existence is utterly meaningless!
You're back.
I'm not the one you were waiting for.
Let me ask you.
Was it you who nurtured me
with your blood essence?
Was it you who taught me to be human?
Was it you
who gave me candy?
Was it you…
who swapped the marriage agreement?
Was it you who left me alone
in this world?
Whether the world recognizes you or not,
I recognize you.
Zhao Ming,
through these 10,000 years,
you must have suffered greatly.
But I'm no longer
the Zhao Ming of the past.
I'm now consumed by dark thoughts.
What if…
What if I don't wish
to walk the old path again
and only want to stay by your side?
Then, I'll follow your will.
In that case, I will be
a dishonorable scoundrel for once.
Mu Xuanling and Xie Xuechen
will never reunite.
Let us take their place
to see all the great mountains and rivers,
to witness this world together.
Even if we are scorned by all beings?
We are so powerful.
Who would dare insult us?
Besides,
wouldn't being a foolish emperor
and a demon empress
be quite wonderful too?
Even if the future world is destroyed?
I've never seen the future world anyway.
All I can see
is you right in front of me.
You little pearl,
still great at cheering people up.
But you don't need
to comfort me with false words.
Zhao Ming,
you've endured 10,000 years
of torment and misunderstanding.
If it were possible,
I truly hope you could follow
your heart and nature.
But I know,
whether 10,000 years ago
or 10,000 years later,
you always place the people and your duty
above your own life and honor.
Zhao Ming,
I trust your choice.
Whatever your decision is,
whether life or death,
I will walk alongside you.
So, this time,
do not abandon me again.
Alright?
But I don't want you
to become someone
consumed by 10,000 years of hatred.
Time is running out.
It's time for my leaving.
I will listen to you,
follow my heart,
and follow my nature.
Let us…
say goodbye here.
Alright.
The decision made
10,000 years ago was mine,
but the suffering, the pain,
and the humiliation for 10,000 years
was borne by you.
During these 10,000 years,
you've endured so much.
What you've been through,
I've experienced.
What you haven't been through,
I've also endured.
Facing trials one after another,
step by step,
I realized I still have attachments
to this world.
As for the next decision, let me make it.
Today, I want only the sun and moon
to exist in this world,
no more deities.
Without deities' permission, how dare you…
Enough nonsense.
We plead for Your Grace
to imprison the evil emperor,
so he can never emerge again.
Erase this figure from humanity!
After 10,000 years,
there's one question
I've always wanted to ask you.
If Hao Tian had not existed back then,
would you have chosen
to imprison me in the Lava?
Fate allows no "what ifs".
This question
has no answer.
Fine.
Let's begin.
Do you regret it?
No regrets.
Evil Emperor Zhao Ming
defied heaven to destroy deities,
descended into a demon,
and was imprisoned in the Lava.
Since I still have
attachments to this world,
let me guard it once more.
Even if I become a demon,
I will have no regrets.
Evil Emperor Zhao Ming,
for selfish desires,
defied heaven to slay deities
and descended into a demon.
The divine artifacts joined forces
to imprison him in the Lava.
You have your choice,
and I have my duty to protect.
No matter how difficult,
I will stand by you until the end.
EVERBRIGHT PALACE
In the end,
did he say anything?
He said
he has no regrets.
Even after 10,000 years,
he's still the same.
And what about you,
Fate?
Will you still stop me?
Can I stop you?
You'll ultimately walk your own path.
Then, this time,
let's not fight, shall we?
Zhao Ming,
thank you for teaching me
what it means to be human,
what love is, and what it means
to have a loving heart.
From this farewell,
10,000 years will pass
before we meet again.
From this day forward,
your name shall be High Cyclic Divinity.
I have bestowed upon you
the power of reversing time.
You will control time.
Greetings to Your Supreme Deity.
Now, everything
has returned to its original course.
It's time for me to follow him.
Fate,
thanks for being my companion
for tens of thousands of years.
Now that Hao Tian is gone
and I'm about to fall into sleep,
you should walk your own path.
When we meet again after 10,000 years,
I hope you will have found
your own happiness.
Alright.
You and I have existed
for tens of thousands of years,
witnessing the passage of time,
experiencing all the joys and sorrows.
I thought I controlled fate,
but in the end, I too was bound by it.
Does this world
truly need the Book of Fate?
Should all living things
be controlled by destiny?
What is the true purpose
of our existence?
Hao Tian no longer exists,
and neither should the Book of Fate.
The Book of Fate is destroyed,
and destiny no longer rules.
All beings
will control their own fates.
Xie…
Xuechen…
Only demonic power
can make the Xuanling Tree blossom.
Who are you?
Didn't you say you wanted
to leave the Dark Abyss
and live an ordinary life?
It's because I believed you
that I brought you to the Snow City.
Here, you can live
like an ordinary person,
cultivate and have fun with them,
without fighting or seizing,
brewing poisonous wine,
or sleeping in unease.
Xuanling,
half a day is too short
to understand the human world.
If there's a chance in the future,
I'll show you the real human world.
Xuanling.
THE END